Come on, make way.
Semua, minggir.
Don't get in the way of the investigation.
Jangan menghalangi penyelidikan.
What happened in there?
Apa yang terjadi?
At least tell us the police's thoughts on the incident.
Apa pendapat kepolisian mengenai kasus ini?
Do you think this is another incident caused by that serial killer?
Apa ini pembunuhan oleh pembunuh berantai itu?
The murdered Jopp couple don't have kids either, right?
Pasutri Jopp yang dibunuh juga tak punya anak, 'kan?
No matter how you look at it, this case is exactly like
Sudah jelas kasus ini mirip
the serial murders of middle-aged couples happening all across Germany.
pembunuhan berantai pasutri paruh baya yang menghantui Jerman.
No comment.
Tak ada komentar.
I've heard that an investigator from the BKA is coming too.
Saya dengar penyelidik dari BKA juga akan terlibat.
So this must be connected to the serial murders.
Pasti terkait pembunuhan berantai.
No comment.
Tak ada komentar.
Oh, geez.
Ya ampun.
It might be faster to just ask the BKA investigator directly.
Mungkin lebih cepat tanya penyelidik BKA langsung.
Please leave it to me.
Serahkan kepadaku.
I promise I'll outwit the other papers.
Liputanku pasti lebih bagus dari koran lain.
Save a big headline space for me.
Siapkan ruang judul berita yang besar, ya.
Thanks again.
Tolong, ya.
Excuse me.
Permisi.
I am Kipper from the Hamburg Tag.
Aku Kipper dari Hamburg Tag.
You're the BKA investigator, right?
Kau penyelidik BKA, 'kan?
I'd like a comment from you.
Mohon komentarnya.
The relationship between this case and the middle-aged couple serial murders…
Hubungan antara kasus ini dan pembunuhan berantai…
Kipper from the Hamburg Talk.
Kipper dari Hamburg Tag.
Here is some special information just for you.
Ini informasi spesial untukmu saja.
It's just as you say.
Kau benar.
This case is one of the middle-aged couple serial murders.
Ini termasuk rentetan kasus pembunuhan berantai pasutri paruh baya.
I knew it!
Sudah kuduga!
Then is the suspect that Japanese doctor?
Jadi, tersangkanya dokter asal Jepang?
I just saw the report.
Aku baru lihat laporannya.
It's the same modus operandi as the serial murders.
Modus operandinya sama seperti pembunuhan berantai itu.
Thanks for the exclusive news. Bye!
Kuterima berita eksklusifnya. Terima kasih.
-Hold it. -Yes?
- Tunggu. - Ya?
The Hamburg Tag is a leading newspaper here, right?
Hamburg Tag koran terbaik di sini, 'kan?
So, your article will be run in leading newspapers all over Germany?
Artikel kalian akan diterbitkan di seluruh Jerman?
Of course.
Tentu saja.
Thanks for your cooperation.
Terima kasih kerja samanya.
I am the culprit.
Aku pelakunya.
I have now become the culprit.
Sekarang aku pelakunya.
Do I knock?
Apa aku mengetuk?
Yes, it's best that the Jopp couple not be cautious around me.
Ya, lebih baik jangan mengagetkan pasutri Jopp.
They easily invite me in and let me into the living room.
Mereka menyambutku dan mengantarku ke ruang tengah.
They are not cautious in the slightest.
Tanpa curiga sama sekali.
The husband's chair.
Kursi suami.
Of course, I sit in the seat for guests.
Aku duduk di kursi tamu.
In a few minutes, the husband will be dead on the floor over there.
Tak lama, si suami akan mati tergeletak di sana.
However, I have not yet taken action.
Tapi, aku belum bertindak.
Where is the wife?
Di mana si istri?
Yes, she is not in this living room yet.
Ya, dia belum ada di ruang tamu ini.
She is making tea in the kitchen.
Dia menyeduh teh di dapur.
Before she can serve the tea,
Sebelum menyajikan teh,
she is stabbed from behind in the kitchen.
dia ditikam dari belakang di dapur.
That means I must begin taking action soon.
Berarti aku harus segera beraksi.
I take my knife out.
Kukeluarkan pisauku.
The husband hurriedly tries to stand up.
Si suami berusaha berdiri.
A single stab.
Satu tusukan.
Oops, I made a mistake.
Wah, gagal.
The husband runs away with an injured left hand.
Si suami kabur dan terluka di tangan kiri.
My next attack is to his right shoulder.
Serangan berikutnya ke pundak kanannya.
Another dumb mistake.
Luput lagi.
I'm acting like a complete amateur.
Gerakanku seperti amatiran.
The husband is calling out to his wife.
Si suami memanggil istrinya,
But the wife in the kitchen cannot hear him.
tapi istrinya di dapur tak bisa mendengarnya.
She is hard of hearing lately.
Belakangan pendengaran istrinya memburuk.
Yes, I know this.
Ya, aku tahu itu.
Make noise. Scream and cry.
Berteriak, menjeritlah.
I can end your wife after killing you.
Istrimu akan kubunuh setelah dirimu.
He's cornered.
Dia terpojok.
A mark from his left hand.
Bekas cap darah tangan kiri.
I've cornered the husband in front of this sideboard.
Aku memojokkan si suami di depan bufet ini.
The final blow!
Serangan terakhir!
No, even now, I haven't dealt the final blow.
Bukan, ini pun bukan serangan terakhir.
The husband dies on the floor five meters from here.
Si suami tewas di lantai, lima meter dari sini.
Why?
Kenapa?
Why did I not deal the final blow here?
Kenapa aku tak membunuhnya di sini?
This…
Ini…
This is the man who killed the Jopp couple?
Ini pria yang membunuh pasutri Jopp?
No, that's not necessarily the case.
Belum tentu begitu.
I'm just asking a small favor of the local residents here.
Aku butuh bantuan warga sekitar sini.
If this man appears, treat him very normally.
Jika pria ini muncul, tolong perlakukan sewajarnya.
Then, contact me promptly.
Kemudian, segera hubungi aku.
That is all I ask.
Itu saja.
I see.
Begitu.
You will not be in danger.
Nyawamu tak akan terancam.
I guarantee it.
Aku jamin.
However, it is surprising such a nasty incident
Tapi, mengejutkan sekali kasus yang sangat keji
happened in a quiet housing district like this.
terjadi di perumahan setenang ini.
Truly, the Jopp couple were such good people.
Benar, pasutri Jopp orang baik.
When I called out to her every morning, the wife always greeted me so cheerfully.
Tiap aku memanggilnya di pagi hari, istrinya selalu menyapa dengan ceria.
You called out to her?
Kau memanggilnya?
The wife was hard of hearing since roughly a year ago.
Sudah setahun pendengarannya memburuk.
What? That can't be.
Apa? Tak mungkin.
It was on the chart from the family doctor.
Tercatat di rekam medis dari dokter keluarga.
She would've barely heard your greetings.
Dia pasti kesulitan mendengar sapaan Anda.
Well, knowing Mrs. Jopp,
Yah, kalau Bu Jopp,
she must've sensed I was there and greeted me.
mungkin dia merasakan keberadaanku dan menyapaku.
The people in this neighborhood don't know she is hard of hearing?
Warga di daerah ini tak tahu dia sulit mendengar?
No, probably not.
Mungkin tidak.
Wow, what an incredible company.
Besar sekali perusahaannya.
Advancing this far at this young age
Seumuranmu sudah sesukses ini,
is no normal feat, Mr. Ziebel.
ini prestasi besar, Pak Ziebel.
No, the auto manufacturer we signed a contract with just happened to do well.
Tidak. Kebetulan kontrak kami dengan pabrik mobil berjalan lancar.
I'd like to give you my condolences for the death of your aunt and uncle.
Aku berbelasungkawa atas kematian paman dan bibimu.
Yes, my aunt and uncle were the only relatives I had left.
Ya, padahal keluargaku tinggal Paman dan Bibi.
The couple had no children,
Pasutri tersebut tak punya anak,
so they must have doted a lot on you, their nephew.
pasti sebagai keponakan, kau sangat dimanja.
Yes, as if I were their real son.
Ya, aku dianggap putra kandung.
So, you'll catch the culprit, right?
Kalian akan menangkap pelakunya, 'kan?
Yes, we're almost there.
Sepertinya kami tahu pelakunya.
It must be the former Japanese doctor, right?
Pasti mantan dokter asal Jepang itu, ya?
You're quite well-informed.
Kau tahu banyak.
Of course I am,
Tentu saja,
as there were incidents similar to this one.
karena ada kasus yang sama dengan kasus ini.
How much will your inheritance be?
Seberapa besar warisan yang kau terima?
What?
Apa?
Well, since Mr. Jopp was such a wealthy person.
Pak Jopp sangat kaya raya.
Is that somehow relevant to this case?
Apa hubungannya dengan kasus ini?
I suppose the only heir to their estate
Satu-satunya pewaris mereka
is you.
adalah kau.
What are you saying?
Apa maksudmu?
That talk is not appropriate at a time like this.
Ini bukan waktunya membahas warisan.
Even if a company is boasting great achievements on the outside,
Meski suatu perusahaan terkesan penuh prestasi dari luar,
on the inside, its financial situation may be desperate.
kondisi keuangannya bisa saja kritis.
Such a thing is quite common.
Itu hal yang umum.
Who the hell do you think you are?
Kau lancang sekali.
It seems like you're insinuating I killed them for the inheritance.
Kau seperti menyindir, aku membunuh mereka demi warisan.
Do not worry.
Tenang.
You have the perfect alibi.
Alibimu sempurna.
You have witnesses that say
Ada saksi yang bilang
you took your secretary and workers to dinner after a business meeting.
kau mengajak sekretaris dan bawahanmu makan usai rapat.
What are you trying to say?
Apa maksudmu?
You are not the culprit.
Kau bukan pelakunya.
Isn't that right?
Benar, 'kan?
Inspector Lunge!
Inspektur Lunge!
Oh, it's you.
Ternyata kau.
What is the meaning of this?
Apa maksudnya ini?
Of what exactly?
Apa maksudmu?
Don't play dumb.
Jangan pura-pura tak tahu.
These past few days, I've been looking into their nephew.
Beberapa hari ini, aku menyelidiki keponakan korban.
His company is excellent at a glance,
Perusahaannya tampak sukses,
but internal conditions are strained due to failed investments and stocks.
tapi sebenarnya mereka kesulitan karena gagal di investasi dan pasar saham.
And you've thoroughly looked into the nephew's company's vicinity.
Kau juga menyelidiki rekanan perusahaan keponakannya.
What is really going on?
Apa maksudnya ini?
Do you really think this case is linked to the middle-aged couple serial murders?
Benarkah kau merasa kasus ini terkait pembunuhan berantai?
The other papers are taking the same stance after our exclusive scoop.
Koran lain kini merujuk ke berita eksklusif kami.
If it is irrelevant to the serial murders,
Jika tak terkait pembunuhan berantai,
that's grave misinformation.
ini informasi keliru.
You're exactly right.
Kau benar.
It was the work of a copycat
Ini ulah penjahat peniru
pretending to be part of the serial murders.
pembunuhan berantai pasutri paruh baya.
I knew it!
Sudah kuduga!
I need to change the article right away.
Artikelnya harus segera kuralat.
-No, it's fine the way it is now. -What?
- Tidak usah, biarkan saja. - Apa?
The article will say it is one of the middle-aged couple serial murders.
Tetap katakan itu termasuk serangkaian kasus pembunuhan berantai itu.
You must be kidding.
Yang benar saja.
Why would I write such lies--
Kenapa aku harus bohong?
Just write it.
Tulis saja.
Despite how this seems, I'm an unimportant journalist.
Begini-begini, aku tetap jurnalis.
Pressuring me will do nothing.
Percuma memaksaku.
Your name was Kipper, was it?
Namamu Kipper, 'kan?
What a beautiful lady you have there.
Dia sungguh cantik, ya?
A warm household.
Rumah tanggamu harmonis.
You have such a wonderful wife and daughter,
Kau punya istri dan putri yang menawan.
but it's only natural you'd want to commit adultery with such a beautiful lady.
Tapi melihat wanita secantik itu, tak heran kau ingin berselingkuh.
Keep it as is.
Pertahankan artikelnya.
No, a special report focusing even more on the middle-aged couple murders is good.
Malah, artikel investigatif yang berfokus pada pembunuhan berantai itu bagus.
That will draw him out for sure.
Pelakunya pasti akan terpancing.
Don't let me down.
Jangan kecewakan aku.
Coming!
Sebentar!
I'd like to ask you something.
Aku ingin bertanya.
Is that so?
Begitukah?
They were such a wonderful couple.
Mereka pasangan yang baik, ya.
Yes.
Ya.
Um, have you heard anything about them having a foster child?
Apa kau tahu soal mereka memiliki anak asuh?
I haven't.
Tidak.
Even for a short while,
Meski sebentar,
have you seen them living with an unfamiliar child?
apa mereka pernah tinggal bersama seorang anak?
No, I haven't.
Tidak.
That couple was very affectionate toward their nephew.
Pasangan itu sangat sayang dengan keponakannya.
Oh, would you like another cup of tea?
Kau mau teh lagi?
No, I'm fine.
Tidak perlu.
Please, I insist.
Tak perlu segan.
There's no mistaking it.
Tak salah lagi.
It's the man from the photo.
Dia pria di foto itu.
He is at my house now.
Dia ada di rumahku.
I see.
Begitu.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Terima kasih atas kerja samanya.
Inspector Lunge, someone is here to see you.
Inspektur Lunge, ada yang ingin bertemu.
Who is it?
Siapa?
It's the nephew of the murdered Jopp couple.
Keponakan dari pasutri Jopp yang dibunuh.
I bet you think I'm the culprit, huh?
Kau curiga aku pelakunya, ya?
Am I right?
Benar, 'kan?
You really think I killed two people for an inheritance, right?
Kau pikir aku membunuh mereka demi warisan, 'kan?
It's true that I'm in a lot of debt.
Memang benar aku punya banyak utang.
The fortune they left me
Kekayaan yang diwariskan
will probably save me from this pinch I'm in.
bisa menolongku dari masalahku ini.
However, I'm not that kind of person.
Tapi, aku bukan orang semacam itu.
You visited me over something like that?
Kau mendatangiku cuma karena ini?
"Something like that"?
"Cuma karena ini"?
What are you saying? You treated me like a culprit!
Apa maksudmu? Kau menuduhku pelakunya!
I have somewhere I must go to now.
Aku harus pergi ke suatu tempat.
Hold it!
Tunggu!
I want you to take back the rude things you said before.
Tarik dulu ucapan lancangmu.
The police are no longer chasing after your tail.
Polisi tak lagi mengincarmu.
The police here have deemed you innocent.
Polisi menganggapmu tak bersalah.
Isn't that enough for you?
Bukankah itu sudah cukup?
Then who do you think is the culprit of this case?
Lalu, menurutmu siapa pelaku kasus ini?
The culprit of this case?
Pelaku kasus ini?
I don't care about that.
Aku tak peduli soal itu.
As long as I can arrest that man.
Selama aku bisa menangkap pria itu.
If there's a bloodstain there…
Jika ada darah di situ…
He messed up?
Dia gagal?
Does that mean
Berarti menurutmu
you think this case wasn't a crime committed by that Japanese doctor?
kasus ini bukan kejahatan yang dilakukan dokter asal Jepang itu?
That is correct.
Benar sekali.
This is what you'd call a copycat crime of the middle-aged couple serial murders.
Bisa dibilang ini kejahatan tiruan kasus pembunuhan berantai pasutri itu.
What makes you think that?
Kenapa kesimpulanmu begitu?
There was something in this case that wasn't in the serial murders.
Ada faktor di kasus ini yang tak ada di pembunuhan berantai itu.
The culprit cornered the victim here.
Korban terpojok di sini.
But instead of here,
Tapi bukannya di sini,
he dealt the final blow over there.
pelaku membunuhnya di sana.
Why?
Kenapa?
Why did he hesitate for a moment?
Kenapa dia sempat ragu?
No.
Bukan.
There's emotion.
Ada keterlibatan emosi.
Emotion?
Emosi?
In the crimes committed by the man I am chasing,
Di setiap pembunuhan oleh pria yang kukejar ini,
the crime scenes are presented like robberies,
TKP-nya dibuat layaknya perampokan,
but you can't feel any emotion from them.
tapi tak terasa adanya emosi.
But the crime scene this time
Tapi di TKP kali ini,
is overflowing with emotion.
dipenuhi dengan emosi.
Just by having his and his victim's face reflected in the mirror,
Saat melihat dirinya dan wajah korban di cermin,
he becomes flustered.
pelaku jadi gentar.
Well, rest at ease.
Tenang saja.
The police here are incompetent.
Polisi di sini tidak becus.
No matter how I look at it,
Dilihat berulang kali pun,
this is the work of a copycat imitating Johan's murders.
ini ulah peniru modus operandi Johan.
How long will this continue?
Sampai kapan terus begini?
How long?
Sampai kapan?
It's been a while.
Lama tak jumpa.
We finally meet, Dr. Tenma.
Akhirnya kita bertemu, dr. Tenma.
I've been searching for a long time.
Sudah lama aku mencarimu.
A very long time.
Lama sekali.
I wanted to have a long talk with you.
Aku ingin mengobrol panjang denganmu.
There's no use in running now.
Percuma kau kabur.
Let's have a nice chat.
Mari kita mengobrol.
How long do you plan to repeat this cycle, Dr. Tenma?
Sampai kapan kita akan mengulangi siklus ini, dr. Tenma?
This is the end.
Selesai sudah.
If only it weren't for you…
Andai saja kau tak ikut campur…
Get off of me!
Minggir!
It was me!
Aku pelakunya!
I killed the Jopp couple!
Aku yang membunuh keluarga Jopp!
I'll turn myself in! Forgive me!
Aku menyerahkan diri! maafkan aku!
I have no interest in you.
Aku tak tertarik denganmu.
Don't get in my way.
Jangan halangi aku.
Dammit…
Sial…
What's with this wound?
Luka apa ini?
At this rate, he'll die from excessive bleeding.
Kalau dibiarkan, dia bisa mati karena perdarahan.
Who did this to Inspector Lunge?
Siapa yang menusuknya?
I'll have to leave him in front of a hospital and run.
Aku harus tinggalkan dia di depan RS, lalu kabur.
Dammit.
Sial.
Are you awake?
Sudah bangun?
Where's the key to the handcuffs?
Di mana kunci borgolnya?
Don't bother looking for your gun.
Tak perlu mencari pistolmu.
I'm holding on to it.
Pistolmu ada padaku.
Anyway, hurry and give me the key to the handcuffs!
Cepat, berikan kunci borgolnya!
I can't do anything like this.
Gerakanku terbatas.
I saw your wound.
Aku sudah lihat lukamu.
Luckily, it hasn't reached your abdominal cavity.
Untungnya, rongga perutmu aman,
However, you're losing a lot of blood.
tapi kau kehilangan banyak darah.
You'll die if it doesn't stop!
Bisa fatal jika dibiarkan!
Confess your crimes, Dr. Tenma.
Akui kejahatanmu, dr. Tenma.
What?
Apa?
The director and two doctors murdered at Eisler Memorial Hospital.
Direktur RS dan dua dokter yang tewas di RS Eisler Memorial.
The middle-aged couple serial murders for the past three years.
Semua pasutri paruh baya yang dibunuh tiga tahun terakhir.
Confess that all of these are your crimes.
Akui semua itu adalah kejahatanmu.
You'll really die!
Kau bisa mati!
Was this all the work of "Johan"?
Apa ini semua ulah "Johan"?
You're searching for Johan, the real culprit?
Kau mencari Johan, pelaku sesungguhnya?
There is no Johan in this world.
Johan itu tidak nyata.
You yourself are Johan, Dr. Tenma.
Johan adalah kau sendiri, dr. Tenma.
Confess.
Akuilah.
There was nothing decent in this abandoned warehouse,
Di gudang ini tak ada barang berguna,
but I did find what I need for first-aid treatment.
tapi ada yang bisa untuk P3K.
Now I need my hands!
Lepaskan borgolnya!
If my hands are free, I can save you!
Jika kau buka borgolnya, aku bisa menolongmu.
You were an outstanding doctor when you were Dr. Tenma.
Padahal kau begitu cemerlang sebagai dokter.
Trying to act like a flawless saint, huh?
Ingin berlagak jadi orang suci, ya?
How many did you kill with those hands?
Berapa nyawa yang sudah kau renggut?
You are wrong.
Kau salah.
When will you change to Johan?
Kapan kau akan menjadi Johan?
When will your good person persona flip to that of a cold-blooded murderer?
Kapan kepribadian baikmu berubah jadi pembunuh berdarah dingin?
You're wrong.
Kau salah.
I am never wrong.
Aku tak pernah salah.
With your blood pressure going down, your consciousness is getting hazy.
Karena tekanan darahmu menurun, kesadaranmu mulai kabur.
At your crime scenes…
Di TKP kejahatanmu…
You shouldn't talk anymore.
Sebaiknya kau diam.
Your crime scenes show no emotion.
Di TKP kejahatanmu, tak terasa adanya emosi.
Stop talking.
Diam.
When you handle the life and death of people every day,
Karena terbiasa menghadapi hidup matinya orang,
emotions disappear, huh, Dr. Tenma?
kau jadi mati rasa, ya, dr. Tenma?
There it is.
Itu dia.
That cool composure is always at the crime scene.
Ketenangan yang selalu tergambar di TKP.
You are truly composed.
Kau sungguh tenang.
You're wrong.
Kau salah.
I had doubts with every surgery.
Aku selalu ragu tiap operasi.
Will I make a mistake?
Bagaimana kalau aku teledor?
Will I finish the job well?
Bisakah kuselesaikan dengan baik?
Will any unforeseen trouble occur?
Akankah ada masalah di tengah jalan?
I was actually trembling.
Aku sungguh gemetar.
A person's life was in my hands.
Nyawa orang berada di tanganku.
In my hands…
Di tanganku…
How could I possibly stay composed?
Mana mungkin aku bisa tenang?
Don't move.
Jangan bergerak.
I'll save you.
Aku akan menolongmu.
I'll shoot.
Aku akan menembak.
I'll stop your bleeding.
Akan kuhentikan perdarahannya.
Where is the key?
Di mana kuncinya?
Is it in your pants pocket?
Di saku celanamu?
I'll shoot…
Akan kutembak…
What a relief.
Syukurlah.
You seem well.
Kau tampak sehat.
You look healthier than when you're at work.
Kau lebih sehat dibanding saat sedang bekerja.
Thank you for worrying about me.
Terima kasih sudah mencemaskanku.
Apparently, the first-aid treatment was done perfectly.
Pertolongan pertamanya sempurna.
The doctor said so.
Kata dokter begitu.
He said you'd be dead by now if it weren't for such correct treatment.
Katanya kau bisa mati jika tak ditangani dengan tepat.
So that means I owe Tenma my life.
Berarti aku berutang nyawa ke Tenma.
Well, Tenma did escape,
Tenma memang kabur,
but Ziebel confessed to the Jopp couple murders.
tapi Ziebel mengaku membunuh pasutri Jopp.
You did great work, Lunge.
Kerja bagus, Lunge.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
-What do you think? -Huh?
- Apa pendapatmu? - Apa?
Dr. Tenma saved Lunge's life.
Dokter Tenma menyelamatkan nyawa Lunge.
That might interfere with Tenma's arrest.
Itu bisa menghambat penangkapan Tenma.
Should we remove Lunge from the Tenma case?
Apa sebaiknya kita tarik Lunge dari kasus Tenma?
Oh, hello.
Halo.
Sorry for all the trouble Inspector Lunge is giving you.
Maaf, Inspektur Lunge jadi merepotkan kalian.
It's no trouble at all.
Tak repot sama sekali.
He gives a nice impression.
Kelihatannya dia baik.
We've told him he doesn't have to rush his rehabilitation so much,
Kami sudah bilang dia tak perlu memaksakan diri saat rehabilitasi,
but he's already gripping the ball and walking down the hallways.
tapi dia terus menggenggam bola dan berjalan di lorong.
He seems to be having a very fun time.
Dia tampak senang.
Fun?
Senang?
Yes, he says all the time
Ya, dia sering bilang
that nothing is more fun than this.
kalau ini sangat menyenangkan.
What is that culprit's name again?
Siapa nama pelakunya, ya?
Oh, right. Tenma.
Oh, ya. Tenma.
He said nothing is more fun than chasing after a culprit like Tenma.
Katanya dia senang sekali mengejar pelaku seperti Tenma.
Eva's Confession
Terjemahan subtitle oleh Rizky Soraya